PIXIU makes four contributions.
First, it introduces FIT,
the first multi-task and multi-modal instruction
tuning dataset for finance,
covering five tasks and nine datasets with one
hundred thirty-six thousand samples.
Second, it introduces FLARE,
the first evaluation benchmark that includes both
financial language understanding and financial prediction.
Third, it introduces FinMA, the first openly released,
instruction-following financial large language model,
achieving state-of-the-art on three financial NLP
tasks and one prediction task.
Fourth, it benchmarks FinMA against existing LLMs,
revealing both their superiority and their key
limitations for finance.